Varsha Kirani Gopinath

Curriculum Vitae

Våxtorpsgränd 10, Älvsjö 12573 Stockholm ,Sweden +46729347913 \bowtie varsha@kth.se



"Success is the ability to go from failure to failure without losing your enthusiasm." – Winston Churchill

Info

Born March 30th, 1985 at Zagreb (Croatia) Citizenship Croatian

Additional J.Salvadora 14, Ciglenica, 44320 Driving License B

Address Kutina, Croatia

LinkedIn http://it.linkedin.com/in/
Elance http://ntrp.elance.com

goivan

Blog http://ntrpivan.blogspot. Skype ivan.ntrp

com

Desidered Employment and Current Skills

System Administrator, DBA, Programmer, Consultant

Over the years, thanks to my thirst for knowledge, I have gained extensive experience in computer science ranging from operating systems to programming languages and platforms upon which the latter are based. Along this path I have continued to improve my approach to problems always trying to implement optimal, generalized and reusable solutions (OOP, Design Patterns). In some academic work opportunities I've been able to demonstrate excellent teamwork skills and capability to collaborate with external groups. Another virtue I possess is the ability to solve almost any computer problem thanks to the excellent information gathering skills and the many years of experience in the computer science field.

Computer Skills

Languages JAVA, JavaScript, C#, C, C++, SQL, T-SQL, PHP, ASP.NET, Jade, HTML5, CSS3, LESS,

PYTHON, LUA, PERL, BASH, \LaTeX , GLSL, HLSL

Platforms Unix, Linux, Windows, Windows Serv- DB MySQL, MSSQL, MongoDB, SSIS

er, IIS, Apache, Lighttpd, Nginx, Node.js, Arduino

Tools VS2010, Eclipse IDE, Netbeans IDE, CMAKE Build system, ANT Build system, Git, SVN, Bzr, Mercurial, All *NIX shell tools, Direct3D 11, OpenGL 4.2, AJAX, jQuery, JSON, Express.js, Socket.io, i18n, Matlab, Office Suite, Photoshop, Gimp, AutoCad, Google SketchUp, Autodesk Maya

Experience

Working

2009-2010 DBA, System Admin, Programmer, Consultant, GUS s.r.l., Venezia, Italy.

Windows Server2008/2010 and MSSQL Server 2008/2010 administration, creation and modification of T-SQL stored procedures and SQL queries, development of ASP.NET/C# based websites, development of C# applications and general computer consultancy.

Accademic

2007-2009 Java Programmer, Università degli Studi di Padova, Padova, Italy.

Group leader of Connectivity plug-in in University of Padova's project PariPari. The aforementioned plug-in has the task of managing the connectivity over our experimental DHT network which aims to offer any type of service in a completely decentralized and distributed way. Among the notions I have acquired the most important are the use of fundamental Design Patterns (Dependency Injection, Abstract Factory, Registry), the use of Java multithreading, file and internet socket access and configuration, the knowledge acquired while developing bandwidth limitation algorithms based on Distributed Token Bucket technique.

Other

Gen 2010 Winning team member at the GGJ 2010, Global Game Jam, Verona, Italy.

Our team took part at GGJ 2010, Verona and won the 1° place jury award and 2° place audience award with the game X-Planets written in C# and based on XNA Platform.

Education

2004-Suspended

Bachelor's Degree in Computer Engineering, *Università degli Studi di Padova*, Padova, Italy.

3 year course in Computer Engineering (ISCED 5A)

1999-2004

Computer Technician high school Diploma, *I.T.I.S. E. Barsanti*, Castelfranco Veneto, Italy.

Course of studies in Informatics, ABACUS experimental project (ISCED 3A)

Languages

Self-assessment European level CEFR (C2 maximum evaluation)

		Comprehension		Speaking		Writing
		Listening	Reading	Interaction	Production	
Italian	Mother Tongue	C2	C2	C2	C2	C2
Croatian	Mother Tongue	C2	C2	C1	C1	B2
English	Advanced	C1	C2	B2	B2	B2

Interests and Hobbies

I love any sport but I prefer Basketball and Ping Pong. I enjoy reading technical and classic literature books but I don't mind psychology and novels either. I love fishing and diving even if I don't practice really often that activities unfortunately.

Extra

QOO Simple PHP framework written with MVC (OOP) programming in mind that I worked on with a friend of mine.

- GitHub Repository
- Qoo Framework Blog